M. L. Parrish Collection of Victorian Novelists, 1806-1958 (bulk 1830s-1930s ): Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Special Collections.
- Series 4: Parrish Correspondence, 1913-1944; 39 boxes (36 partial)
  - Trollope, Anthony (lists), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 8)
  - Trotter, Mrs. Elizabeth, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 9)
  - Charles E. Tuttle Company, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 10)
  - U - V (General), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 11)
  - Ulizio, B. George, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 12)
  - Ulysses Bookshop, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 13)
  - Union Library Catalogue, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 14)
  - Van Antwerp, William C., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 15)
  - Van Nosdall, George A., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 16)
  - van Patten, Nathan, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 17)
  - Varied Thrush (bird), undated; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 18)
  - Victorian Lady Novelists (bibliography by Parrish), undated; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 19)
  - Wa - We (General), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 1A)
  - Edgar H. Wells and Company, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 1B)
  - Wf - Wz (General), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - Walmsley, Patricia, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - Wanamaker, John and Rodman, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - Weaver, Warren, undated; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - Weber, Carl J., undated; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 6)
  - Wells, Gabriel, 1923-1934; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 7)
  - Wells, Gabriel, 1935-1943; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 8)
  - Wesleyan University, undated; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Widener Library, Harvard University, undated; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - Williams Book Store, undated; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 3)
  - Williams, Sidney Herbert, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 4)
  - Wilmerding, Lucius, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - Wilson, Carroll A., 1927-1929; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 6)
  - Wilson, Carroll A., 1930-1931; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 7)
  - Wilson, Carroll A., 1932-1933; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 8)
  - Wilson, Carroll A., 1934-1935; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 9)
  - Wilson, Carroll A., 1936-1937; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - Wilson, Carroll A., 1938-1939; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - Wilson, Carroll A., 1940-1944; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - Winterich, John T., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Wise, Thomas J., undated; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 5)
  - Wister, Frances A. and Owen, undated; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - Woore, Frank, undated; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 7)
  - Wormser, Richard S., undated; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 8)
  - Wroth, Lawrence C., undated; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 9)
  - X - Y - Z (General), undated; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 10)
  - Zanetti, J. Enrique, undated; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 11)
  - Zeitlin, Jake, Inc., undated; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 12)
  - Zucker, Hyman, undated; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 13)
  - "Macleod of Dare", 1841-1898; 147; 1 volume / 234 leaves
    Autograph manuscript, with holograph corrections, of Black's novel MACLEOD OF DARE.
  - "The Martian", 1894-1895; 148; 1 volume / 6 leaves
    Consists of a partial French manuscript for Du Maurier's THE MARTIAN: early working draft, 5 1/4 pages, in ink on rectos of gray sheets, with numerous revisions. Included is a typed English translation (12 pp.), with inked corrections. THE MARTIAN was Du Maurier's last novel, which was published posthumously (New York, 1897). He was just able to finish correcting proofs before he died; this portion of the manuscript apparently was greatly altered in its final, published form.